Identification_Information:
  Citation:
    Citation_Information:
      Originator: REQUIRED: The name of an organization or individual that developed the data set.
      Publication_Date: REQUIRED: The date when the data set is published or otherwise made available for release.
      Title: CRelief.img
      Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: remote-sensing image
      Online_Linkage: \\tornado\research3\CoastEnergy\gisdata\orginals\NOAA_Topo\coastrelief\grid\CRelief.img
  Description:
    Abstract:
      This data set was created on November 2, 2009 using elevation data from the NOAA National Ocean Service Hydrographic Data Base's (NOSHDB) GEOphysical DAta System (GEODAS) Grid Translator (Design-A-Grid). The downloaded data contains XY coordinates and heights in meters. The data extends past the OCS plan boundary.

      For more information, please visit http://www.ngdc.noaa.gov/mgg/geodas/geodas.html.
    Purpose: To be used for the Southeast Ocean Based Renewable Energy project as a resource to analyze and identify potential alternative energy facilities within Georgia waters and federal waters beyond state jurisdiction.
  Time_Period_of_Content:
    Time_Period_Information:
      Single_Date/Time:
        Calendar_Date: REQUIRED: The year (and optionally month, or month and day) for which the data set corresponds to the ground.
    Currentness_Reference: REQUIRED: The basis on which the time period of content information is determined.
  Status:
    Progress: REQUIRED: The state of the data set.
    Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency: REQUIRED: The frequency with which changes and additions are made to the data set after the initial data set is completed.
  Spatial_Domain:
    Bounding_Coordinates:
      West_Bounding_Coordinate: -81.716583
      East_Bounding_Coordinate: -77.111583
      North_Bounding_Coordinate: 33.000750
      South_Bounding_Coordinate: 29.999250
  Keywords:
    Theme:
      Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus: REQUIRED: Reference to a formally registered thesaurus or a similar authoritative source of theme keywords.
      Theme_Keyword: bathymetry, elevation, depth
  Access_Constraints: REQUIRED: Restrictions and legal prerequisites for accessing the data set.
  Use_Constraints: REQUIRED: Restrictions and legal prerequisites for using the data set after access is granted.
  Native_Data_Set_Environment: Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3000
Spatial_Data_Organization_Information:
  Direct_Spatial_Reference_Method: Raster
  Raster_Object_Information:
    Raster_Object_Type: Pixel
    Row_Count: 2001
    Column_Count: 3070
    Vertical_Count: 1
Spatial_Reference_Information:
  Horizontal_Coordinate_System_Definition:
    Geographic:
      Latitude_Resolution: 0.000000
      Longitude_Resolution: 0.000000
      Geographic_Coordinate_Units: Decimal degrees
    Planar:
      Planar_Coordinate_Information:
        Planar_Coordinate_Encoding_Method: row and column
        Coordinate_Representation:
          Abscissa_Resolution: 0.001500
          Ordinate_Resolution: 0.001500
    Geodetic_Model:
      Horizontal_Datum_Name: D_WGS_1984
      Ellipsoid_Name: WGS_1984
      Semi-major_Axis: 6378137.000000
      Denominator_of_Flattening_Ratio: 298.257224
Distribution_Information:
  Resource_Description: Downloadable Data
  Standard_Order_Process:
    Digital_Form:
      Digital_Transfer_Information:
        Transfer_Size: 0.000
Metadata_Reference_Information:
  Metadata_Date: 20100105
  Metadata_Contact:
    Contact_Information:
      Contact_Organization_Primary:
        Contact_Organization: REQUIRED: The organization responsible for the metadata information.
        Contact_Person: REQUIRED: The person responsible for the metadata information.
      Contact_Address:
        Address_Type: REQUIRED: The mailing and/or physical address for the organization or individual.
        City: REQUIRED: The city of the address.
        State_or_Province: REQUIRED: The state or province of the address.
        Postal_Code: REQUIRED: The ZIP or other postal code of the address.
      Contact_Voice_Telephone: REQUIRED: The telephone number by which individuals can speak to the organization or individual.
  Metadata_Standard_Name: FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata
  Metadata_Standard_Version: FGDC-STD-001-1998
  Metadata_Time_Convention: local time
  Metadata_Extensions:
    Online_Linkage: http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html
    Profile_Name: ESRI Metadata Profile
